hey guys uh welcome back to the second
video in the series of uh building the
DZ logo animation um this time I'm going
to be showing you how to uh create the
Dynamics chain that you saw in the
animation uh where the magnet came down
and and picked up the piece of sheet
metal um so with that let's get started
let's just go ahead and start uh
creating a chain link um for this we're
going to use a rectangle
spline
and we're going to change the width to
200 and the height we can leave at 400
CM then we're going to turn on
rounding and we're going to change the
radius to
100 okay and then we're going to
grab the inside spline and the reason I
use inside instead of circle is that you
have more more control over the the
geometry the amount of detail in each
chain link so grab
that and um we're going to change the
radius down
to uh about
25 okay and then we're going to grab um
sweep
nerb and take the inside and the
rectangle and put it under the sweep
nerb and there we have it our first
link and I'm going to up the detail
um this we're going to change the amount
of sides on the inside to
eight and then gives it a little
smoother look to it and uh if we turn on
J shading lines you'll notice that it's
got a lot more detail on the top and
bottom we can
probably um turn that down a tad and do
that um just go into the rectangle and
you'll see under immediate intermediate
points if you change change this around
just for like uniform it kind of makes
it distributes the uh subdivision
throughout the whole link um actually
we're going to leave it on adaptive and
if you up the
angle turn it up um you'll notice
that um there's a Le there's a less
subdivision so we're going to change
that to 17 looks good to
me
okay and next thing we're going to do
we're going to change the uh pivot point
of each link to the top so if we turn
off the sweep nerb so you can just see
the rectangle spline we want the axis to
be here at the top Center so um turn on
our axis manipulation tool um turn on
snapping and we're going to rip it off
tear it off menu enable snapping turn on
3D turn off construction grid grid line
turn on
point and then just go ahead and pull
whoops
right
okay oh I'm sorry it needs to be sweep
nerves needs to be selected so go ahead
and grab that and pull it up think okay
close that out turn this off turn this
off and we can turn sweep nurse back on
okay and then we can disable the lines
go back to Dr
shading so there we have it our first
link
um okay so let's go ahead and uh clone
these um to create a series of links um
it's going to be under mograph and
cloner and just take the sweep nerb and
put it under the cloner
and uh we start with
three um we're going go ahead and change
that to
eight and then the p.y we want to change
that down to a negative
value and you'll see why here
later
um
330 worked pretty good for me and uh
make sure the mode is set to
linear and to rotate every other link
you just need to change the
R.H to uh
90° and every other link will be
positioned the right
way so there we have
it okay
um the first thing I'm going to the
first way I'm going to show you is uh
to create a Dynamics chain is one that
takes a little more um processing power
um this one didn't quite work for me as
well um the links were falling apart and
U it was just a little slower on my
machine but uh so I'm going to show you
how to do this first and then we'll
change it to I'll show you how to do it
um as I did in my video so um just right
click on sweep nerb and add a rigid body
tag under the simp imulation
tags okay
and um since each mesh has um a hollowed
out Center we need to tell Cinema 4D
that it's a moving mesh so change the
shape to moving
mesh
okay and that's very important so okay
and then we need a way to hold this
chain up um cuz right now if you you hit
play it would just fall right on out of
the screen um so we're just going to use
um
Taurus change the orientation
toax just put it up
here um segments we'll just change that
to 12 and pipe segments to 12 is
fine and I'm just going to rename this
to
handle and go ahead and add rigid body
tag to this as well and for shape we're
going to change this to static mesh cuz
it's not going to
move we'll animate the position of it
but it's not going to move dynamically
with the other links
so okay so right now we could go ahead
and hit play and uh you'll see what
happens here first I'm going to up the
uh amount of frames from 90 to 900 drag
this
out okay so hit
play um
I apologize for my machine it's not the
fastest thing in the
world um and there we have it there's
our first problem I didn't really move
it that much and it broke apart um one
thing you can do let me just rewind and
then undo the what I moved here if you
go into edit and then project settings
and if you click Dynamics Tab and then
the expert tab if you change change the
steps per frame from say 5 to
20 it's going to up the uh amount of uh
processing power it takes to kind of
figure out how the Dynamics are moving
so it's going to be run a little slower
but
uh the links are going to
stay connected a lot
better I moved it kind of quick but it's
still you you'll notice that it stays
connected with
well take my word for it it does work
better but my machine is just not very
very good so I
apologize but it does work it does help
I'm going to undo this and now I'm going
to show you uh the way I went about it
for my animation that uh didn't give me
hardly any problems at all so going to
go ahead and change this back to
five
and first thing we need to do is make
each one of these its own separate
object so if you click on cloner and you
right
click go to current state to
object it creates a null and each link
will be under its own null or under its
own its own object so um we can go ahead
and just get rid of the whole cloner
group
um and this is the reason I did uh a
negative value when when I did the
cloner um
because when I did the -330 under p.y um
if you start with zero it starts with
the top link and goes down the
list um if we did a positive value um
clicking on number seven would have been
the top Link in our chain and it's just
easier um but uh we can actually go
ahead and get rid of the null so just
take it out and delete
cloner and we're going to rename each
one of these objects just to their
numbers it's just easier you'll
see
two
three
four
five
six and
seven
okay and
okay and these already have a Dynamics
tag attached to them because when I did
the current state to object under the
cloner it carried that information down
into each one of these and they they all
have moving mesh which is good that's
what we
want so with that let's go ahead and add
in our connector which will connect each
one of these together so go under under
um
simulate d Dynamics
connector okay and then we're just going
to move this in between handle and
zero and for the first one we're just
going to rename
it handle to Z you don't need to name it
that uh it just makes it easier to
understand um and then under the type of
of connector we're going to change that
to ball and
socket and we're going to turn off
Collision ignore collisions
and uh for object a it's going to be
handle and object B you guessed it
zero so
okay and the thing with connectors they
need to be in the right position for
them to work correctly
so um you'll notice on the ball and
socket connector it's it's got like a
yellow top and a blue
bottom um just moveth this down so that
um it's right above the first object so
handle we want it right above it so
right here we just want a little bit of
yellow showing so that would be good
right
there and uh I apologize this is very
tedious but I promise you it works
great when it when it's all set up
properly so we're going to go ahead and
copy this down the line this is really
tedious
uh four and five five and six six and
seven and rename each of
these
zero to
one one
oops one to
two two to three this just makes it
easier later on
three to four
four to
five 5 to
six six to 7 okay and then click on each
one and drag in the objects where they
need to be so zero is object
a and one object
B
one to
two
three three to
four I apologize this is really boring
here four to
five five to
six six to
seven okay there we have it now we have
to line them all up in their proper
locations so we already did the first
one I'm just going to quickly uh
put them into place and then I'll go in
and tweak them a little bit later so
move them
down and between each
link okay so zero to one zoom
in make sure the yellow
part of the connector is just sticking
above um the top
link so this
one want to move that down
slightly two to three move it down a
little
bit three to
four move it
up four to five
move it down
slightly five to
six and six to
seven all
right there we have
it now if we go ahead and hit
play should
work just fine
um shouldn't have any issues with the
chain breaking apart or anything like
that um sometimes it can get tangled up
a little bit but
uh and I apologize this is just not a
very good computer to test this on but
um yeah I'm going to go ahead and
undo change that
oops so but it it really does work a lot
better than um how it was before you
won't have any any links breaking
apart
um so this worked great for me and the
good thing about this is I can attach a
d another Dynamics object um to the
bottom oh there it goes it's degrading
my viewport here because my computer's
so slow
um but I can go ahead and attach another
Dynamics object to the bottom and use
that to uh pick up another object like
in my scene I picked up the piece of
metal
um um let's see
here if we were to attach say say we
were making a wrecking ball um going to
the
object um let's create
a uh it's getting late okay
sphere and let's just go ahead and
change the size here that looks good
move it
down and change this name to
ball move it to the
bottom and we also need to assign this
um uh Dynamics a rigid body tag so I'm
just going to copy it from number seven
put it here um and the ball needs to be
a moving mesh as
well um so it's already set to that um
and we need to create another connector
from seven to ball so just take six to
seven and copy it
down and then just name it seven to
ball and then make sure you drag in
your objects
seven to ball and then for
this just move the connector so it's
just above so it just sit like that
okay and then when I was doing my tests
here uh you want to um up the Val the
mass of the ball so if we click on the
rigid body tag of the ball go to the
mass Tab and instead of using World
density we're going to use a custom Mass
and change that to about
400 and this varies depending on how big
your objects are on the scene so um with
this 400 should work um work
okay and uh on this machine it's
probably not going to run the best but
uh let's just see what happens hit
play um there we have it
it kind of looks like it has a little
bit of weight to it in the
bottom but
uh yeah you might need to up the the
mass of the ball or change the gravity
in your scene and it should work a
little better but it'll definitely stay
attached like I didn't have any problems
when I did my magnet in in the original
animation
so that's that um and you can you could
throw in a floor here
and go ahead and just add a rigid body
and change the Collision type
to static
mesh what's going on
here Okay I lied we I needed to hit
pause first but uh add in a floor put it
on here in the bottom
okay
and add in a static mesh rigid
body okay and then just uh hit
play you can pull it down
and yeah it definitely needs more weight
it's just floating
there but uh yep it should land lands on
there just fine
so I really apologize for how slow my
computer is but um you get the idea I
think
so um hopefully this helps you guys out
um that's all I wanted to show you today
for um um the chain so uh if you have
any questions feel free to email me or
um use the comments and uh I'll be sure
to reply as soon as I
can thanks a lot guys have a great day